coopercenter.org 2015-03-17

# CCPS Privacy Statement | Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service

**PRIVACY STATEMENT**

The Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service has developed this privacy statement to affirm our strong commitment to your privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site.

**Information Automatically Logged**  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. We do not link your IP address to your personal identity. The logging is simply to ensure access to our server and for troubleshooting any accessibility and/or security problems.

**Registration Forms and Online Registration**  
Our site's registration and application forms require users to provide contact information (like their name, email, and postal address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, gender or income level).

Contact information, stored in our database, is used to register users for events, contact users about those events and others offered by the Center, and for purposes pertaining to programs the user is actively participating in such as tracking points for Certification Programs.  The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary.

Financial information that is collected is used to verify payment for registration and purchases and/or to bill the user for products and services. Our Online system does not collect or store credit card or bank account information. We only store information pertaining to amount paid, method of payment and payment status. At the end of the registration or purchase process, the user may choose to pay via credit card or electronic check using the credit card gateway which is hosted and maintained by a 3rd party vendor contracted by UVA. 

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We do not collect data without your knowledge. Any demographic or profile data submitted by you for a particular program/event or survey will be used for internal use only.

**Order Forms**  
Our site uses an order form and online ordering system for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect contact information (like their email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the order forms is used to ship purchases and mail information about our organization. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. We do not store credit card numbers or bank account information. We  
only store information pertaining to amount paid, method of payment and  
payment status.  At the end of the registration or purchase process, the user may choose to pay via credit card or electronic check using the credit card  
gateway which is hosted and maintained by a 3rd party vendor contracted  
by UVA.

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We do not collect data without your knowledge. Any demographic or profile data submitted by you for a particular program/event or survey will be used for internal use only.

**Surveys**  
Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like email address), and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the surveys is used for internal purposes only. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site We do not collect data without your knowledge. Any demographic or profile data submitted by you for a particular program/event or survey will be used for internal use only.

**External Links**  
This site contains links to other sites. The Cooper Center is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

**Public Forums**  
This site makes listserves, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.  

**Supplementation of Information**  
This site supplements the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties. We subscribe to the Virginia Review Database for local government contact information.  
Choice/Opt-Out  
    1.    You can send email to [IT@mail.institute.virginia.edu](mailto:IT@mail.institute.virginia.edu)  
    2.    You can send mail to the following postal address:  
    3.    2400 Old Ivy Road, Charlottesville, VA 22903   
    4.    You can call the following telephone number: 434-982-5522

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: [IT@mail.institute.virginia.edu](mailto:IT@mail.institute.virginia.edu)
